More fun than Fanny! More Fanny than funny!
Around the World with Fanny Hill is a comedy film directed by Mac Ahlberg.
In Stockholm, Fanny Hill is tired of being a housewife, and she suspects that her husband
Roger, a TV-commercial director who's surrounded by starlets, is cheating on her.
So, she sets a trap for him with her friend Monica, files for divorce,
and heads to Hollywood, with Monica, to meet film stars.
She falls into a film career, with lots of nude
scenes, and as it takes her from L.A.
to Hong Kong and Venice, Roger follows her, jealous, hoping to win her back.
In every city, she acts and she seduces, making comedy out of
both; but does her heart still belong to Roger?
It's on to Munich to find out.
Fanny Hill, played by Shirley Corrigan.
Roger Boman, played by Peter Bonke.
Monica, played by Gaby Fuchs.
Peter Wild, played by Bo Brundin.
Meatball Model, played by Christina Lindberg.
William, played by Walter Buschhoff.
Funny Girl is a 1968 American biographical musical film directed by William Wyler and written by
Isobel Lennart, adapted from her book for the stage musical of the same title.
It is loosely based on the life and career of comedienne Fanny Brice and her
stormy relationship with entrepreneur and gambler Nicky Arnstein.
Produced by Brice's son-in-law Ray Stark (and the first film by his company Rastar), with music and lyrics by Jule Styne and Bob Merrill, the film stars Barbra Streisand (in her film debut reprising her
Broadway role) as Brice and Omar Sharif as Arnstein, with a supporting cast featuring Kay Medford (also reprising her Broadway role), Anne Francis, Walter Pidgeon, Lee Allen and Mae Questel.
A major critical and commercial success, Funny Girl became the highest-grossing film of 1968 in the United States and received eight
Academy Award nominations at the 41st Academy Awards including Best Picture, with Streisand winning Best Actress.
Streisand tied for the award with Katharine Hepburn for The Lion in Winter which marked
the first and (as of 2025) only tie to happen in the category's history.
In 2006, the American Film Institute ranked the film No.
16 on its list commemorating AFI's Greatest Movie Musicals.
Previously it had ranked the film No.
41 in its 2002 list of AFI's 100 Years...100 Passions, the songs
"People" and "Don't Rain on My Parade" at No.
46, respectively, in its 2004 list of AFI's 100 Years...100
Songs, and the line "Hello, gorgeous" at No.
81 in its 2005 list of AFI's 100 Years...100 Movie Quotes.
Funny Girl is considered one of the greatest musical films ever made.
In 2016, Funny Girl was deemed "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant" by the United
States Library of Congress, and selected for preservation in the National Film Registry.
The film explores themes of blow job, travel, erotic movie.
The tone is lighthearted.